JACK SENECHAL

1901 8th St, Berkeley, CA 94710 415-779-2701 • jacksenechal@gmail.com jacksenechal.com/resume • github.com/jacksenechal

Introduction

I am an engineer with a passion for the future. I have a deep interest in the architecture of complex systems and facilitating emergence. I value foresight, innovation, multidimensional thinking, and appropriate application of technology. I am existentially intolerant of the status quo.

Current professional interests include building tools for community self-organization, including tools for identity, trust, collaboration, annotation, and discovery. I'm fascinated with application and data ecosystems, and would like to see more flexibility and crossover between systems.

My ideal workplace has a vibrant environment of innovation, a strong team practicing **Agile** methodologies, and a culture of excellence. It is more than a day job, it is a platform to launch big ideas. I bring **10**+ **years of industry experience**, an appetite for challenges, and a broad understanding of the technological landscape.

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

Programming experience with **Ruby**, Rails, **JavaScript**, CoffeeScript, Node.js, jQuery, D3, PHP, ActionScript, Flex, and SuperCollider. Limited experience with C/C++, Java, Perl and Python.

Most comfortable developing with **Vim on Linux**.

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

Enlightened Structure

- Co-founded the Enlightened Structure metaproject to create an open, decentralized, collaborative application and data ecosystem.
- Envisioning and prototyping of tools and applications such as reputation exchange, forking-based collaboration, and visualization and navigation the global semantic graph.
- Research and synthesis of information on candidate technologies.
- Code contributions to related projects (primarily written in Ruby and JavaScript).
- Ongoing contributor to Building the Collaborative Internet community.

Skype Links Chrome Extension

- A Chrome extension to make callto: or skype: links out of phone numbers on web pages.
- 47,000 users, 4 stars, 900 g+ plus ones.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts from the University of North Carolina at Asheville (May, 2003)

- Major in mathematics, minor in computer science
- Undergraduate research in mathematics
- Graduated with distinction in mathematics

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Clairvision School of Meditation

- Multiple volunteer projects over 15 years as a student.
- Overhauled the e-commerce and fulfillment systems, reducing order processing time by a factor of 10. Payment gateway and paid-postage integrations using APIs from Stripe and EasyPost. Custom Ruby/JavaScript shipping and fulfillment application taking data from the existing system and presenting it in an intuitive interface for volunteers to process orders, pack items, and print shipping labels. (2013-2014)
- Helped to develop electronic music systems using open source tools. Trained a team of musicians in basic programming. Wrote arpeggiator and sampler patches for SuperCollider. Prototyped Reactable clone in PureData. (2011)
- Developed Java search engine for knowledge base, website development including JavaScript shipping estimator. (2000)

Superluminal Systems August 2013 - January 2014

- Helped to develop and launch the first client site based on the Superluminal Learning Management System.
- Collaborated on innovative user interface elements using D3 and CoffeeScript.
- Wordpress plugin wrangling, development and customization.

OpenTest Pro, LLC 2008 - 2011

- Founded the company to provide educational resources relating to automated testing and continuous integration using open source tools in a PHP environment.
- Activities include technical writing, web application development in Ruby on Rails and Flex, studio voiceover recording, and project management.

Independent Contracting 2004 - 2009

- Turnbull & Asser shirtmakers (2008-2009). Built a virtual showroom for their bespoke department, allowing users to browse fabrics and place orders. Ruby on Rails backend, Flash frontend.
- Idance.net video dance instruction (2004-2005). Designed and implemented an e-commerce site in PHP and MySQL. Pay-per-download purchasing, content browsing and searching, back-end for the client to manage the site with detailed admin reports on purchases and user activity.
- Various smaller websites and components.

OnForce, Inc - New York, NY June 2006 - December 2007

- Programmed features and updates to the OnForce platform.
- Introduced automated testing with PHPUnit. Implemented tests for OnForce's public-facing API. Unit testing infrastructure included PHPUnit with a custom test database refreshing mechanism, Selenium, and CruiseControl.
- Integrated OnFoce platform with Salesforce APIs to provide up-to-date customer information for sales and support teams.
- Project managed the implementation of Salesforce throughout the company, and oversaw the administration of the application.

JBA Network - Asheville, NC June 2003 - December 2006

 Project manager and lead programmer for medium-scale web application, mynewsletterbuilder.com. Designed the application and coded the initial release. Later oversaw the ongoing development team for the project. MNB remains one of the primary revenue sources for the company.

- Developed a modular, evented, MVC programming framework for PHP.
- Concept development, project management, and programming for other company products and services, including www.jukeboxalive.com and www.byregion.net.
- Systems administration and networking (Linux, Windows).

US Navy FNMOD - Asheville, NC May 2001 - August 2001

Programmer, database designer for the Fleet Numerical Meteorology and Oceanography
Detachment. Migrated Navy weather data from a flat text format to a MySQL database. Wrote a
Java application for quality checking weather data, and converting it to a MySQL-accessible
format.

Freelance - Sydney, Australia December 1999 - December 2000

• Web designer, programmer. Developed a Java search engine applet for a CD-ROM based knowledge bank. Various other web development and graphic design projects.

Internet Safety Association - Asheville, NC December 1998 - December 1999

• Designer, computer technician. HTML and JavaScript programming, graphic design, web design and management, network management, computer repairs and upgrades.

Various - Asheville, NC 1996 - 1998

 Assorted computer related jobs and volunteer work, including CAT-5 and fiber-optic network installation, web development, desktop publishing, technical writing, computer repair, and technical support.

Excellent References Available Upon Request